I want to show you how virtual environments work in Python.
我想展示一下 Python 虚拟环境的工作原理
Unfortunately, you might run into different issues
但是不幸的是 你可能会遇到不同的问题
depending on your operating system and Python installation.
因为操作系统和 Python 安装的不同
The classroom workspace uses
教室的 workspace 使用的是
an Ubuntu Linux operating system and a special Python installation known as Anaconda.
Ubuntu Linux 操作系统 使用 Anaconda 安装的 Python
In this particular case,
在这种特定的情况下
there are some issues with the virtual environment package,
有几个虚拟环境软件包的相关问题
and the quick fix is to run conda update Python and then hit Enter.
快速解决的方法是输入 conda update python 然后点击回车
Running this command takes a while,
运行这个命令需要一段时间
so I've already done it before recording.
我在录屏之前已经完成了
If you're not using Ubuntu or Anaconda,
如果你使用的不是 Ubuntu 或 Anaconda
you shouldn't need to run this command first.
你不需要先运行这行命令
If everything is working correctly and you're using Python three,
如果一切运行顺利并且你使用的是 Python3
the virtual environment package should already be installed.
虚拟环境软件包应该已经安装好了
You can type Python -m venv
你可以在终端输入 python -m venv
and then your virtual environment name and hit Enter in the terminal.
然后是你的虚拟环境名称 然后点击回车
Venv_name is the name you want to give to your virtual environment.
venv_name 是你想要给虚拟环境起的名称
You can name it anything you want.
你可以改为自己想起的名字
If you go over here into the workspace area,
如果你在 workspace 中完成操作
you'll see there's a new folder called venv_name.
会看到这里出现了一个新的文件夹 venv_name
Inside of that is a Python installation.
在该文件夹中是一个 Python 安装
Now you can type source venv_name/bin/activate,
现在你可以输入 source venv_name/bin/activate
hit Enter, and you'll see that the virtual environment is now activated.
点击回车 然后你会看到现在虚拟环境被激活了
So, anything you install now will get installed into
那么现在你安装的任何东西都会安装在
the virtual environment instead of your default Python installation.
虚拟环境 而不是默认的 Python 安装环境
You'll notice that the command line now shows in parentheses
注意一下命令行开头用括号括起来的
the virtual environment name at the beginning of
虚拟环境名称
the line indicating that you're using that virtual environment.
表明你正在使用该虚拟环境
Now I'm going to change to the directory where I have my Python package and setup file,
现在我将修改目录到我的 Python 软件包和 setup 文件所在目录
and then I say pip install.
然后像之前一样输入 pip install .
like before. Now I've installed the distributions package
这样就将 distributions 软件包
into the virtual environment instead of
安装到了虚拟环境中
the default Python environment that's installed on the computer.
而不是计算机默认安装的 Python 环境
That's really it for virtual environments.
使用虚拟环境真的很合适
The benefit is that you can experiment with Python
优势在于可以在不影响默认 Python 安装的情况下试验 Python
You can always just delete the virtual environment folder from your computer,
你可以在计算机中直接删除虚拟环境的文件夹
and there shouldn't be really any consequences
而不会对默认的 Python 安装有任何影响